JANICE LIN

UI/UX Designer

janicelin852.github.io/JaniceLin

janicelin852@gmail.com

+886-978-930887

UI/UX designer with background in design, research and education. Before becoming a UI/UX designer, I worked as an information management specialist at the National Center for Suicide Prevention. I discovered my passion for product design while assisting clients in resolving platform problems. Later, I work in an industrial networking company's IIoT department to design complex and cross-platform systems. As a designer, I enjoy solving complex problems through the design process and continue to improve my abilities by joining a reading club and keeping up with design trends.

EXPERIENCE

UI/UX Designer

Jun 2021 - Now

ORing Industrial Networking Corp.

- Software and hardware IoT, I/O communication module product solution design.
- Designed SaaS (Software as a platform), including the energy management system, smart streetlight system and remote I/O.
- Built, redefined, and maintained the design system for Web and App.
- Collaborated with project managers and developers.

Information Specialist

Aug 2019 - May 2021

National Center for Suicide Prevention

- Manage a digital learning site for 10,000+ healthcare professionals.
- Assist users to troubleshoot website problems.
- Graphic design, event photography, video filming.

EDUCATION

M.S. in Digital Learning and Education

National Taiwan University of Science and Technology

Taiwan, Taipei | Sep 2017 - Jul 2019

B.A. in Digital content and techlonogy

National Taichung University of Education

Taiwan, Taipei | Sep 2017 - Jul 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

Google UX Design certificate unofficial public welfare book club

Volunteer

Introduction to Human-Centered Design

IDEO.org

SKILLS

Wireframing

Prototyping

Usertesting

User interface design

Visual design

TOOLS

Figma/Sketch Adobe Caeative Suite

HTML/CSS

LANGUAGE

English

Mandarin chinese